<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://yoon-group.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://yoon-group.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-02-03T18:51:05+00:00</updated><id>https://yoon-group.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Yoon Research Group</title><subtitle>#A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Workstations</title><link href="https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/workstations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Workstations"/><published>2025-12-28T18:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-28T18:40:00+00:00</updated><id>https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/workstations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/workstations/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="how-to-access-the-group-workstations">How to access the group workstations</h2> <p>Three workstations are available in Quantitative Hydrogeology Lab.</p> <table data-toggle="table" data-url="/assets/json/table_ip.json"> <thead> <tr> <th data-field="name">workstation</th> <th data-field="ip">IP</th> </tr> </thead> </table> <p></p> <p>The ID, SSH password, and VNC port number will be created and provided to each member upon request to Sean.</p> <table data-toggle="table" data-url="/assets/json/table_port.json"> <thead> <tr> <th data-field="id">ID</th> <th data-field="port">port number</th> <th data-field="workstation">accessible workstations</th> </tr> </thead> </table> <p></p> <p><br/></p> <ul> <li>An example of setting up a GUI connection on the workstation ‘yoon-group-2’ using the credentials of ‘lindsey’ is shown below.</li> <li>Download and install turboVNC viewer according to the OS of your local machine (<a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/turbovnc/">Download turboVNC Viewer</a>).</li> <li>For Windows users, PuTTY is required (<a href="https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/latest.html">Download PuTTY</a>). For mac OS users, skip to step 2.</li> <li>Always close the VNC server session when you are finished with your work. If you need to run a process in the background for an extended time, use the <a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/screen-command-in-linux-with-examples/">screen</a> command to run it in a screen session.</li> </ul> <div> 1. Run PuTTY and enter IP address 10.227.17.189 and a title for your session as shown below. The example below is test; you can have your own title. Click Save to save your settings for future use, and then click Open to initiate your SSH tunnel. <center><img src="/assets/img/ws1.png" alt="drawing" width="70%"/></center> <br/> 2. Once a terminal is open, type your id and ssh password as below. (For mac OS, open terminal and login by ‘ssh lindsey@10.227.17.189.) <center><img src="/assets/img/ws2.png" alt="drawing" width="90%"/></center> <br/> 3. Change your ssh password as you want for security. To change the password, type ‘passwd’. <br/> 4. Run a VNC server on your assigned port number by ‘vncserver :[Your Port Number]’. You will be asked to create your VNC password (8 digits). If you want to change the password later, type in vncpasswd. <center><img src="/assets/img/ws3.png" alt="drawing" width="90%"/></center> <br/> 5. open turboVNC viewer in your local machine, type in IP address + port number, click ‘Connect’ <center><img src="/assets/img/ws4.png" alt="drawing" width="70%"/></center> <br/> 6. type in your VNC passwd (8 digtis). <center><img src="/assets/img/ws5.png" alt="drawing" width="60%"/></center> <br/> 7. Once you are connected, you should see the default desktop. It should look something like this: <center><img src="/assets/img/ws6.png" alt="drawing" width="90%"/></center> <br/> 8. Again, always close the VNC server session ("vncserver -kill :2") when you are finished with your work. If you need to run a process in the background for an extended time, use the <a href="https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/screen-command-in-linux-with-examples/">screen</a> command to run it in a screen session. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Quantitative_Hydrogeology_Lab"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to access group workstations]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Codes</title><link href="https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/github/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Codes"/><published>2025-10-15T20:36:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-15T20:36:00+00:00</updated><id>https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/github</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/github/"><![CDATA[<div class="repositories d-flex flex-wrap flex-md-row flex-column justify-content-between align-items-center"> <div class="repo p-2 text-center"> <a href="https://github.com/yoon-group/spectral_data_processing"> <img class="only-light w-100" alt="yoon-group/spectral_data_processing" src="https://github-readme-stats-gamma-red-69.vercel.app/api/pin/?username=yoon-group&amp;repo=spectral_data_processing&amp;theme=default&amp;locale=en&amp;show_owner=false&amp;description_lines_count=2"/> <img class="only-dark w-100" alt="yoon-group/spectral_data_processing" src="https://github-readme-stats-gamma-red-69.vercel.app/api/pin/?username=yoon-group&amp;repo=spectral_data_processing&amp;theme=dark&amp;locale=en&amp;show_owner=false&amp;description_lines_count=2"/> </a> </div> <div class="repo p-2 text-center"> <a href="https://github.com/yoon-group/sink_rise_discharge"> <img class="only-light w-100" alt="yoon-group/sink_rise_discharge" src="https://github-readme-stats-gamma-red-69.vercel.app/api/pin/?username=yoon-group&amp;repo=sink_rise_discharge&amp;theme=default&amp;locale=en&amp;show_owner=false&amp;description_lines_count=2"/> <img class="only-dark w-100" alt="yoon-group/sink_rise_discharge" src="https://github-readme-stats-gamma-red-69.vercel.app/api/pin/?username=yoon-group&amp;repo=sink_rise_discharge&amp;theme=dark&amp;locale=en&amp;show_owner=false&amp;description_lines_count=2"/> </a> </div> <div class="repo p-2 text-center"> <a href="https://github.com/yoon-group/gc_data_processing"> <img class="only-light w-100" alt="yoon-group/gc_data_processing" src="https://github-readme-stats-gamma-red-69.vercel.app/api/pin/?username=yoon-group&amp;repo=gc_data_processing&amp;theme=default&amp;locale=en&amp;show_owner=false&amp;description_lines_count=2"/> <img class="only-dark w-100" alt="yoon-group/gc_data_processing" src="https://github-readme-stats-gamma-red-69.vercel.app/api/pin/?username=yoon-group&amp;repo=gc_data_processing&amp;theme=dark&amp;locale=en&amp;show_owner=false&amp;description_lines_count=2"/> </a> </div> <div class="repo p-2 text-center"> <a href="https://github.com/yoon-group/cdom_fdom_peakPicking"> <img class="only-light w-100" alt="yoon-group/cdom_fdom_peakPicking" src="https://github-readme-stats-gamma-red-69.vercel.app/api/pin/?username=yoon-group&amp;repo=cdom_fdom_peakPicking&amp;theme=default&amp;locale=en&amp;show_owner=false&amp;description_lines_count=2"/> <img class="only-dark w-100" alt="yoon-group/cdom_fdom_peakPicking" src="https://github-readme-stats-gamma-red-69.vercel.app/api/pin/?username=yoon-group&amp;repo=cdom_fdom_peakPicking&amp;theme=dark&amp;locale=en&amp;show_owner=false&amp;description_lines_count=2"/> </a> </div> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Quantitative_Hydrogeology_Lab"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Group GitHub Repositories]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Expectations</title><link href="https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/expectations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Expectations"/><published>2024-12-20T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-20T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/expectations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/expectations/"><![CDATA[<p>Many parts of this note are from my mentor’s and colleagues’ notes.</p> <p>This note aims to establish shared expectations within our research group. As the PI, my primary goal is to cultivate a supportive and inspiring research environment where motivated and talented students and postdocs can conduct impactful research, grow as researchers, and build strong foundations for their careers. I believe this can only be achieved through shared understanding and goals.</p> <p>We aim to create a balanced group structure that supports both productivity and creativity. While overly rigid structures can hinder innovation, well-defined group dynamics can enhance it. Your input is crucial in shaping our group’s structure and goals. Please feel free to share your thoughts or questions. I will continuously update this document to incorporate feedback from group members and to reflect my evolving mentoring experiences.</p> <h2 id="research-projects">Research Projects</h2> <p>I will ensure that each member in our group (except undergraduates) has at least one leading research project that can result in a first-author journal publication. We will collaboratively develop research projects that align with your interests and funding opportunities. While I will propose potential research directions, our goal is to find projects that inspire you and contribute to the group’s overall objectives.</p> <p>Your initiative and ownership are essential for project success. I will provide guidance and support, but you will take the lead in exploring creative solutions and producing high-quality results.</p> <h2 id="be-self-motivated">Be self-motivated</h2> <p>I expect all members to be self-motivated. If you are not self-motivated, academic research may not be the right fit for you. Imagine two members: Joe and Erin. Joe is well trained for data analysis and experimental technique. He is given great projects by his advisor and executes tasks with his well-trained skills, but rarely makes an effort to formulate problems and solutions on his own. In contrary, Erin is less skilled than Joe, but she constantly brainstorms about what problems are interesting for what reasons and thinks deeply about technical solutions; she even brings these problems to her advisor and take ownership of her projects. In a short run, Joe’s works may be better in quality and quantity because they’re his advisor’s ideas. But in a long run, it’s Erin who will emerge as a successful researcher.</p> <p>Advisors often encounter advisees who do exactly what they’re told to do and nothing more. It’s unlikely that they will continue research in a long run. High standards and a passion for discovery are fundamental to our work. If you share these values, I am committed to supporting your growth and success.</p> <h2 id="focus">Focus</h2> <p>Knowledge workers, like us, should be aware that we live in a world of distractions. A widespread belief is that multitasking—the ability to work on diverse projects—is a mark of productivity and competency. However, this is often untrue. More frequently, this belief leads to a situation where knowledge workers are busy achieving little.</p> <p>In fact, the only way to achieve true growth as a researcher is to single-mindedly pursue a research project from beginning to end and produce tangible results, often in the form of publications. I highly recommend the book “<a href="https://www.google.com/books/edition/Deep_Work/B_L8CAAAQBAJ?hl=en&amp;kptab=overview">Deep Work</a>” by Cal Newport. I’ve read it several times and still return to my bookmarked pages for reminders about the importance of focused work and the helpful tips it provides.</p> <h2 id="work-ethics">Work Ethics</h2> <p>Academic research demands dedication and a strong work ethic. While I value flexibility, consistent engagement is crucial. Rather than focusing on the number of hours worked each week, it is essential that the work is conducted rigorously and creatively, which can be achieved through strong motivation and taking ownership of your research.</p> <p>One of the key advantages of academic research is the flexibility to choose your working hours. Therefore, I am flexible about when you work, but I ask that you be present in the office or lab for at least half of each working day. This fosters a supportive research environment with both me and your lab mates and ensures that you are available for ad-hoc meetings necessary for collaborative research.</p> <p>I believe that a balanced life is essential for productivity, health, and happiness. I encourage all members to maintain a balanced lifestyle. As a research mentor, I am always open to hearing your concerns and sharing my experiences to help you sustain your passion and purpose.</p> <h2 id="absences--vacations">Absences &amp; Vacations</h2> <p>Occasional absences for personal reasons, such as family events or short trips, are understandable. Please inform me if you’ll be away for more than a day. All group members are entitled to up to three weeks of vacation per year. Please coordinate extended absences with me in advance to avoid conflicts. If you need additional time off, please discuss it with me.</p> <h2 id="togetherness">Togetherness</h2> <p>I expect all members to be respectful of others. Your academic reputation and career success depend not only on your work but also on the work of our group members. Everyone’s success benefits us all. This applies to everyone, including myself. My professional success is tied to the success of my students and postdocs, and vice versa. Most importantly, a supportive and caring research environment enhances everyone’s well-being. We should all support one another. Harassment or discrimination will not be tolerated.</p> <h2 id="lab-works">Lab Works</h2> <p>I expect all group members to adhere to two critical components when conducting lab work: <strong>safety</strong> and <strong>organization</strong>. We will designate individuals to oversee the Quantitative Hydrogeology Lab and Geofluids Lab. Please help maintain a pleasant lab environment and consult with these individuals if you have any questions.</p> <h4 id="safety">Safety:</h4> <ul> <li>Be fully aware of the hazards associated with chemicals and equipment.</li> <li>Wear appropriate personal protective equipment (PPE), including a lab coat, goggles, gloves, and closed-toe shoes.</li> <li>Always communicate potential hazards and recommended safety precautions to lab mates and your advisor.</li> <li>Leave a written note detailing hazards when absent from the lab.</li> </ul> <h4 id="organization">Organization:</h4> <ul> <li>Maintain a clean and organized workspace.</li> <li>Properly clean glassware and dispose of waste according to regulations.</li> <li>Keep a detailed and accurate lab notebook, including chemical labels, dates, and procedures.</li> <li>Write legibly in your lab notebook so that others can easily replicate your experiments.</li> </ul> <h2 id="code-development">Code Development</h2> <p>I expect each member to be proficient in at least one of the following programming languages: MATLAB, Python, or R. Code development will be co-managed by both you and me using Git and GitHub. Please learn these tools for efficient version control, collaboration within the lab, and code sharing. UF subscribes to LinkedIn Learning, where you can access free courses on Git, such as <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/learning/git-essential-training-19417064?trk=learning-serp_learning-search-card_search-card&amp;upsellOrderOrigin=default_guest_learning">Git Essential Training</a>.</p> <p>High-quality and functional code with well-organized comments are essential. Please consider the following two guidelines for writing well-structured code:</p> <ul> <li>Consistency: Use proper indentation and descriptive names for variables and functions.</li> <li>Readability: Write clear and concise comments throughout your code.</li> </ul> <p>These practices benefit not only others who may need to reference your code but also yourself when revisiting it later.</p> <h2 id="individual-meetings">Individual Meetings</h2> <p>We will hold regular weekly one-on-one meetings to discuss your research progress. Scheduling individual meetings will be managed through the Outlook calendar. Please link the Outlook calendar to your mobile scheduling app (e.g., Google Calendar).</p> <p>For these meetings, we will keep updating PowerPoint slides that will be posted on the Outlook calendar. The meeting slides are useful for reviewing what we previously discussed and for being reminded of the next steps. Before meetings, include graphs, data, and discussion points. Always remember that clarity is more important than slide quality. Please try to update the slides with new results and discussion points by 8 AM on the day of our meeting. This allows me to review them beforehand and make our time together more productive.</p> <p>In addition to presenting your results, please include a slide outlining potential next steps. This practice will help you become a more independent researcher, even though we may develop different directions for next steps during our meeting. During the meeting, both you and I will edit as necessary. After our meeting, please revisit the slides and edit as needed.</p> <p>I am available for unscheduled meetings as needed. Feel free to stop by my office to discuss urgent matters between our regular meetings. For non-urgent questions or requests, such as paperwork, please send an email.</p> <h2 id="group-meetings">Group Meetings</h2> <p>We will hold regular bi-weekly group meetings to foster collaboration and knowledge sharing. Attendance is mandatory unless you are absent due to travel. Meeting formats will vary. You will present your research to the group once per semester. Primarily, group meetings will focus on discussing high-impact journal papers or other research articles with significant findings. Papers introducing new theoretical frameworks or providing overviews are less suitable for in-depth discussion.</p> <p>Discussion leadership will rotate among group members. If you are in charge of leading the discussion, prepare a brief (2-3 minute) introduction summarizing the paper. Encourage active participation by highlighting key points, weak points, and potential research directions. All group members should carefully read the selected paper before the meeting.</p> <h2 id="attending-conferences">Attending Conferences</h2> <p>I will support the conference attendances of group members who are presenting talks or posters related to group projects where I am the PI or co-PI. All final versions of conference abstract submissions must be pre-approved.</p> <p>Your presence and presentation at conferences represent our entire group; therefore, the quality of your presentation is essential. To ensure high standards, both you and I will comprehensively review and finalize your talk or poster. Please refer to the linked <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Xc6TBsv3B4CSAPdgLvax8Lya6qKjUgvv/view?usp=drive_link">note</a> that outlines guidelines for creating an excellent presentation.</p> <p>Attending conferences offers a valuable opportunity to enhance your professional profile, connect with fellow scholars, and establish potential collaborations. Make the most of this opportunity. After the conference, we will hold a group meeting to share interesting and relevant talks or posters encountered during the event.</p> <h2 id="expectations-to-pi">Expectations to PI</h2> <p>You can and should expect the following from me. <strong>If you find me deviating from these, please let me know.</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Scientific Guidance</strong>: Offering comprehensive scientific guidance to help you produce significant, rigorous, and innovative research outcomes.</li> <li><strong>Professional Development</strong>: Supporting your progress toward your professional goals, including career advice and detailed feedback on job application materials.</li> <li><strong>Positive Leadership</strong>: Striving to take the initiative and set a positive example for the entire team.</li> <li><strong>Equality and Respect</strong>: Treating all group members with equal respect and valuing your time.</li> <li><strong>Efficient Workflow</strong>: Avoiding delays in manuscript submissions and providing thorough feedback on drafts of manuscripts, posters, and conference talks.</li> <li><strong>Lifelong Mentorship</strong>: Serving as a lifelong mentor, engaging in this role to the extent that you wish.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Quantitative_Hydrogeology_Lab"/><category term="Geofluids_Lab"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Expectations in Yoon Research Group]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PDMS Process</title><link href="https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/pdms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PDMS Process"/><published>2024-12-20T13:46:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-20T13:46:00+00:00</updated><id>https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/pdms</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yoon-group.github.io/notes/pdms/"><![CDATA[<p><a class="h6" href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/ovfp5intqaz0waqlpzo8v/PDMS-processing-procedure.docx?rlkey=ugijj6qobk0wcw8kj1m3483oq&amp;st=b0lbuj6y&amp;dl=0" target="_blank">PDMS Process</a></p> <p>This note outlines the procedure for preparing, curing, and bonding PDMS (Polydimethylsiloxane) to produce PDMS-based microfluidic chips. PDMS is a silicon-based organic polymer commonly used in the fabrication of microfluidic devices due to its flexibility, optical transparency, and biocompatibility. This process should be followed after photomask printing and the fabrication of patterned chips using photoresist. The current procedure is based on existing literature and will be updated as we gain more experience with PDMS chip fabrication.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Geofluids_Lab"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to make PDMS chips]]></summary></entry></feed>